Guide to the Lucinda Cawley political and commemorative textiles collection, 1860s-2008.
Cawley, Lucinda political and commemorative textiles collections
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Lucinda Cawley political and commemorative textiles collection, 1860s-2008.
8433
Cawley, Lucinda Reddington,
2.5 cubic feet.
Textiles
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Approximately 100 commemorative textiles, buttons, photographs and other ephemera relating to United States presidential campaigns, United States military, World's Fairs, as well as other events from the late 19th century through the early 21st century.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Lucinda Cawley co-authored "Saved for the People of Pennsylvania: Quilts from the Collection of the State Museum of Pennsylvania" with Lorrane Ezbiansky and Denise Nordberg. She built a collection of antique fraktur-inscribed quilts and used old census records to research the individuals whose names appeared on the quilts. These quilts are now part of the Lucinda Cawley Collection at the International Quilt Study Center and Museum at the University of Nebraska-Lincoln. Cornell's collection consists of Lucinda's other passion of collecting political and commemorative textiles.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Approximately 100 commemorative textiles, buttons, photographs and other ephemera relating to United States presidential campaigns, United States military, World's Fairs, as well as other events from the late 19th century through the early 21st century.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cawley, Lucinda Reddington,
Subjects:
Presidents -- United States -- Election.; Elections -- United States.; Political campaigns -- United States.; Exhibitions -- United States -- History -- 19th century.; Exhibitions -- United States -- History -- 20th century.; Campaign buttons.; Campaign songs.; Political slogans.; Campaign paraphernalia.
Form and Genre Terms:
Textiles.; Buttons (information artifacts).; Photographs.; Prints.; Portraits.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Similar political textiles appear in the Susan H, Douglas Political Americana Collection, #2214 and can be viewed as part of an on-line exhibit.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Presidential
Series II. Military
Series III. General Political
Series IV. World's Fair/Exhibition
Series V. Media and Miscellaneous
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Presidential
  - Barak Obama Fabric, 2008; 42in x 60in (Box 3)
    Cut of fabric. His portrait with a map of Africa.
  - Barak Obama Fabric, 2008; 43.5in x 63in (Box 3)
    Cut of fabric. His portrait with American flags and the slogan "Yes we can."
  - Barak Obama Fabric, 2008; 25.75in x 45in (Box 3)
    Cut of fabric. His portrait with the phrase "Akwaaba."
  - Ronald Regan and George Bush Handkerchief, 1985; 7.5in x 7.75in (Box 1, Folder 3)
    "Celebrating Term Two - 50th Presidential Inaugural"
  - Jimmy Carter Scarf, 1976; 21.in x 21.25in (Map-case Folder 1)
    His portrait with peanuts.
  - McGovern for President Scarf, 1972; 31.5in x 31.5in (Box 3)
  - Hubert Humphrey Shift Dress, c. 1968; 20in x 40in (Box 3)
    Shift dress made from cotton scarf fabric.
  - George Wallace Necktie, c.1968 (Map-case Folder 3)
  - Lyndon B. Johnson Sash, c. 1964; 4.75 x 32.5 (Map-case Folder 3)
  - AuH20 Embroidery for Barry Goldwater, c. 1964; 2in x 4in (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Uses the chemical signs for gold and water.
  - John F. Kennedy Sash, c. 1960; 4.75in x 32.5in (Map-case Folder 3)
  - Richard Niixon Satin Ribbon, c. 1960; 2.5in x 7in (Box 1, Folder 2)
    "Our Next President Richard M. Nixon"
  - Richard Nixon Thimble, c. 1960 or 1968 (Box 1)
    "Sew it up for Nixon"
  - Dwight D. Eisenhower Toile in Tan, c. 1953; 36in x 36in (Box 3)
    Cut of fabric with motifs from Eisenhower's life.
  - Dwight Eisenhower Handkerchief, c. 1952; 12.25in x 13.5in (Box 4)
    "I like Ike" with elephant
  - Franklin Delano Roosevelt Textile Portrait, c. 1930s or 1940s; 11in x 11.75in (Box 4)
    Woven Jacquard; from the Textile Department at Georgia Tech
  - Alfred Smith Scarf (Broadside), c. 1928; 14in x 19in (Box 4)
  - Herbert Hoover Scarf (Broadside), c. 1928; 14in x 19in (Box 4)
  - Herbert Hoover Thimble, c. 1928 (Box 1)
    "Hoover, Home, Happiness"
  - Taft and Sherman Bandana, 1912; 17.in x 17.5in (Box 4)
  - Benjamin Harrison Bandana, 1888; 19.25in x 20in (Map-case Folder 1)
    "Protection of Home Industries"
  - Cleveland and Thurman Bandana (x2), 1888; 21.5in x 24in (Map-case Folder 1)
  - Advertisement of presidential candidate Grover Cleveland for "The Bazaar" shop in Brockport, NY, c. 1888 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Horace Greeley Fabric, 1872; 5.5in x 6in (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Swatch of cotton fabric
  - James Monroe Cigar/Cigarette Silk, undated; 1.75in x 2.75in (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - John Quincy Adams Cigar/Cigarette Silk, undated; 1.75in x 2.75in (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Andrew Jackson Cigar/Cigarette Silk, undated; 1.75in x 2.75in (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Martin Van Buren Cigar/Cigarette Silk, undated; 1.75in x 2.75in (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - William H. Harrison Cigar/Cigarette Silk, undated; 1.75in x 2.75in (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - John Tyler Cigar/Cigarette Silk, undated; 1.75in x 2.75in (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - James K. Polk Cigar/Cigarette Silk, undated; 1.75in x 2.75in (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Millard Fillmore Cigar/Cigarette Silk, undated; 1.75in x 2.75in (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Ulysses S. Grant Cigar/Cigarette Silk, undated; 1.75in x 2.75in (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 2 Postcards of Presidential Quilts, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Reproduction Roosevelt and Gardner - Repeal Prohibition 1932 Campaign Coaster, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Beer Coaster from the FDR Library
  - Pins
    - Colin Powell, 2008; 2.25in diameter (Box 1, Folder 12)
      "President Colin Powell"
    - Hilary Clinton, 2008; 2.25in diameter (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Barak Obama/Joe Biden, 2008 or 2012; 1.75in diameter (Box 1, Folder 12)
      "Change for the Better"
    - John McCain, 2008; 2.25in diameter (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - John Edwards, c. 2004 or 2008; 2.25in diameter (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - John Kerry, c. 2004; 2.25in diameter (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Ronald Regan and George Bush, c. 1980; 1.5in diameter (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Gerald Ford, c. 1976; 1.5in diameter (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Ronald Regan, c. 1975-1976; 1.25in diameter (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Richard Nixon and Spiro Agnew, 1968; 1.25in diameter (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Women for Nixon, c. 1968; 1.25in diameter (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Richard Nixon Tab, c. 1968 (Box 1)
    - Landon Knox, c. 1936; 1.5in diameter (with felt flower) (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Landon Knox, c. 1936 (Box 1)
      Lapel pin
- Series II. Military
  - Desert Storm Bandana, c. 1990-1991; 21in x 22in (Map-case Folder 2)
  - Souvenir de France Handkerchief, 1945; 9in x 9in (Box 1)
  - "To My Sister" Iceland Painted Handkerchief, 1943; 8.5in x 8.5in (Box 1)
  - Military Nurse lithograph, c. 1940s (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Welcome Home - Uncle Sam Flag, c. 1940s; 36.5in x 37in (Map-case Folder 5)
  - Flag of the Allies World War I Handkerchief, c. 1919; 10.25in x 10.5in (Box 1)
  - Souvenir d'Arras (World War I) Handkerchief, c. 1917; 13.5in x 13.75in (Box 4)
  - Service Over There Banner, unadted; 11.5in x 17.5in (Box 4)
  - Admiral George Dewey Arch Fabric, c. 1899; 14.5in x 29in (Map-case Folder 4)
  - Tunis Handkerchief, undated; 8in x 8in (Box 1)
    Hand embroidered
  - United States Navy Handkerchief, undated; 10.25in x 10.5in (Box 1)
  - United States Air Corps Handkerchief, undated; 10.25in x 10.75in (Box 1)
  - Sweetheart U.S.A. Handkerchief, undated; 10.75in x 10.75in (Box 1)
  - Sister U.S.A. Handkerchief (x3), undated; 9in x 9in (Box 1)
  - United States Navy Sister Handkerchief, undated; 10.75 x 10.75 (Box 1)
  - Thule Air Base, Greenland Pillow Cover, undated; 20.5in x 20.5in (with fringe) (Box 4)
  - United States Army - Camp Bowie Texas Pillow Cover, undated; 19.5in x 20in (with fringe) (Box 4)
  - United States Army Hankie Holder, undated; 4.75in x 11 (Box 1)
  - Notre Dame de Paris Handkerchief, undated; 10in x 10in (Box 1)
  - Aloha Hawaii Handkerchief, undated; 10in x 10in (Box 1)
  - Painted flowers Handkerchief, undated; 10in x 10in (Box 1)
- Series III. General Political
  - Statue of Liberty Centennial Bandana, 1986; 21in x 22.5in (Map-case Folder 2)
  - 1776-1976 Fabric Calendar, 1976; 32in x 72in (Box 3)
  - Presidential Signature Scarf, 1976; 20in x 20in (Map-case Folder 1)
  - "76" scarf, 1976; 21in x 21.5in (Map-case Folder 2)
  - The Democratic Party Handkerchief (up to Harry Truman) (x2), c. 1950s; 12.25in x 13.5in (Box 4)
  - The Democratic Party Handkerchief (up to Lyndon Johnson), c. 1960s; 12.25in x 13.5in (Box 4)
  - Queen Elizabeth's Coronation Handkerchief, 1953; 10in x 10.25in (Box 1)
  - Democrats handkerchief, c. 1960s; 14.5in x 15in (Box 4)
    Designed by Pat Richards
  - Souvenir of Washington D.C. Handkerchief (with Franklin Delano Roosevelt), c 1932-1945; 14.5in x 15in (Box 4)
  - Francis E. Willard Banner, 1938; 28in x 38in (Map-case Folder 4)
    Founder of the National Woman's Christian Temperance Union
  - Washington D.C. Map Scarf, 1933; 25.5in x 25.5in (Map-case Folder 4)
  - The Sesquicentennial Philadelphia - 150 Years of Independence Flag, 1926; 4.75in x 6.5in (Box 1, Folder 13)
    On wooden stick
  - Star-Spangled Banner Centennial Scarf, 1914; 15.5in x 16in (Box 4)
  - Flags of North American and Europe Quilt, undated; 70in x 70in (Box 2)
    Label reads "Tobacco Premiums Flag Quilt." Includes flags of European countries prior to World War I
  - Hail Columbia Fabric Swatch, c. 1876; 4.5in x 4.5in (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - United States Centennial - 1776-1876 Fabric Swatch, c. 1876; 4.5in x 4.5in (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Justice and Peace - George Washington Fabric Swatch, c. 1876; 4.5in x 4.5in (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Justice and Peace - George Washington Reproduction Fabric Swatch, c. 1990s-2000s; 5in x 9.5in (including selvedge) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Greetings from the Mexican Boarder Handkerchief, c. 1916; 14.5in x 16in (Box 4)
  - ALJA and Russian Table Runner, 1942; 17in x 37in (Map-case Folder 3)
    Cotton table runner with embroidery
  - Continental Quilting Congress Scarf, undated; 8in x 33.5in (Map-case Folder 3)
  - Made in the U.S.A. Bandana, undated; 31in x 31in (Map-case Folder 2)
  - Crocheted American Flag Handkerchief, undated; 10.25in x 10.75in (Box 1)
  - Tobacco Flannel - "America" and flags of Central and South America, c. 1910-1920; 8.5in x 10.5in (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 2 Postcards of American Flag Quilts, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Series IV. World's Fair/Exhibition
  - New York World's Fair Scarf, 1964-1965; 27.5in x 28in (Map-case Folder 4)
  - Seattle World's Fair Handkerchief, 1962; 14.5in x 15in (Box 4)
  - New York World's Fair Scarf, 1939; 19in x 21in (Map-case Folder 2)
  - San Francisco World's Fair Scarf, 1939; 28.5in x 29in (Map-case Folder 4)
  - Chicago World's Fair Handkerchief, 1934; 11in x 11in (Box 1)
  - Pan-American Exhibition Scarf, 1901; 23.75in x 23.75in (Map-case Folder 4)
  - Pan-American Exhibition Handkerchief, 1901; 12in x 12in (Box 1)
  - Souvenir of the World's Fair in Chicago Scarf, 1893; 16in x 16in (Box 4)
  - Philadelphia Centennial International Exhibition Bandanna, 1876; 25.25in x 26.25in (Map-case Folder 4)
  - Crystal Palace Handkerchief, 16in x 16.5in (Box 4)
- Media and Miscellaneous
  - Presidential Campaign Songs 1789-1996, 1999; 1943 (Box 1)
  - Cross Stitch Pattern for an eagle and "E Pluribus Unum", undated (Box 4)
  - Japanese Silk Handkerchief, 1933; 11in x 11.25in (Box 1)
  - Fabric Book "A was an Archer" - children's book - Dean's Rag Book London, c. 1905; 8in x 11in (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Photographic Print of Civil War Era Woman, c. 1860s (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Tobacco Flannel in the shape of a "rug" with (Native American?) image of a swastika, undated; 5.75in x 8.25in (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Tobacco Flannel in the shape of a "rug" with Yale University Logo, undated; 5in x 8.25in with fringe (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - The Crying Handkerchief, undated; 16 x 16.5 (Box 4)
  - Quilt Labels, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    From the "Rising Sun Collection" and the Little Sisters Quilt Collection" at the Smithsonian
SEPARATED MATERIAL
Books - cataloged individually in the Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections
Collins, Herbert Ridgeway Threads of History: Americana Recorded on Cloth 1775 to the Present, 1979 (many of the textiles in this collection are similar to those found in this book)